These biscuits are good.
Say... Will you tell me what my suit is?
That guy you're paired with...
He's a murderer, you know?
What?
I saw him in the papers.
He's Sunato Banda,
an infamous killer
who took the lives of four women.
I think he was sentenced to death.
That's a lie.
It's the truth.
I think he's the Jack of Hearts.
There are five of us left.
I'm sure that the Jack will go
on the offensive now.
Let's tell each other's suits.
You're in a good position now.
The Jack trusts you.
You're the only one
who can lie to the Jack.
In other words,
the only person who can end this game
is you.
It seems you still can't trust me.
In any case, to make sure
that Banda is telling you the truth,
I think you and I should
tell each other's suits.
Do you really think I can trust you?
It doesn't matter to me if you can't.
The more choices you have, the better.
Isn't that right?
I swear to you, I'll tell the truth.
It's also true that Banda is a murderer.
I can't trust you.
Well, I'm sure we'll see
who's right this round.
Your suit is spade.
Tell me what mine is.
Hey.
I told you yours.
I didn't agree to this deal.
Heart.
What's wrong?
The Jack of Hearts...
is that guy.
I also suspected him.
But don't worry.
He'll die this round.
That Banda guy...
We need to be extremely cautious of him.
The young guy who first lied
to that big guy and killed him...
It was this guy
who told the young guy to lie.
I saw him do it.
He looks kind.
But in reality,
he completely lacks empathy for others.
He only has a theoretical understanding
of other people's feelings.
He's the kind
who kills people for pleasure.
I think he's the Jack.
There are only five people left,
and I've lost my partner.
A minute ago,
that Matsushita guy told me my suit.
But I don't think he trusts me,
so I think he probably lied.
You know, you look really honest.
I don't think you'd lie.
Could you please tell me what my suit is?
Of course, I'll tell you
what your suit is.
And I'll be truthful.
You sure seem to be
infatuated with that Yaba guy.
That's how a con man works, you know.
I won't beat around the bush.
Are you the Jack of Hearts?
The only way
I can answer that question
is to say it could be either you or me.
Just as I thought,
I doubt you and I can get along.
Your suit...
is heart.
Mine...
is club, right?
These ones are better.
Five people left.
There are two pairs.
The Jack will surely move this round.
Well...
This must be the final round.
Heart.
Thank you.
Diamond.
Spade.
Okay, tell me mine now.
It is time to make your guess.
Everyone, please enter a prison cell.
One person per cell, please.
ROUND 13
The suit Matsushita told me
is most certainly a lie.
And Kotoko ignored my question.
This means
I'm either diamond or spade.
Ultimately, I'll have to go
with intuition.
Please make your guess.
I won.
You're the Jack of Hearts,
just as I thought.
How...
I saw when you and the murderer,
Banda, paired up.
Let's be friends.
Even if
you were impressed by what Banda said,
there's no way anyone could be
accepting of a stranger so quickly.
There aren't many people
who'd approach someone like me.
And if you tried to kill me,
then you're either scheming,
you're just a plain idiot,
a psychopath, or a sociopath.
Why you...
To find that out, I decided to play along.
You thought that you could control me.
Also, you were confident
that you were superior to everyone else.
And the more important your position is,
the more your confidence manifests itself.
Like the Jack of Hearts.
Sorry, but it's not me.
Banda is the Jack.
It's such a shame,
but it's not him.
You were in cahoots with Kotoko.
I told Kotoko her real suit.
But still, she died.
This means
somebody else was controlling Kotoko.
Then...
Then that guy must be him.
When I was in the cafeteria,
each of you would always come
and get snacks around the same time.
What do you think?
Who should go first?
Every time,
you'd get the same type of snacks.
You and Kotoko used
the cafeteria to communicate.
Spade...
Both of you pretended
that you were being controlled.
Those snacks come in four flavors.
You used the snacks that you got...
to confirm with each other
whether your suit was right or not.
Then...
you told Kotoko
to lie to me about my suit.
Diamond.
I honestly did trust that woman.
Except at the end.
When did you three start working together?
In the opening announcement for this game,
they said that it's a test
of how much you can trust others.
We simply followed that advice.
The surest way to ensure trust
isn't through persuasion, manipulation,
or even domination,
nor is it through brainwashing, hypnotism,
deception, or fear.
It's equality.
Just as I thought,
I doubt you and I can get along.
By the way,
why are you participating
in the games in this land?
Until now,
I've never been in a land
as beautiful as this one.
Because I believe
this is the only world
that is worthy of my control.
I think you and I might be very similar.
I thought the same thing.
Trust is important in this game.
I think I've finally found
an equal partner worthy of my trust.
Still...
It's still possible that
one of you is the Jack of Hearts!
Yeah, maybe I did try to deceive you guys,
but you can't declare
I'm the Jack of Hearts just based on that!
I wouldn't be so sure.
What?
If those two were certain
that you were the Jack of Hearts,
then why didn't Banda lie to you
during the last round and try to kill you?
They must have made a deal
and are going to try
to get some info out of you.
Round 14 will now start.
What are you going to do to me?
One doesn't often get the chance to have
a nice long conversation with a citizen.
You'll tell us everything
you know about this land.
It's unfortunate that I can't kill you.
But I can still have fun with you.
TEIO PRISON
We couldn't get that much out of him.
I guess he couldn't handle it
and guessed wrong on purpose.
And we even told him
the truth about his suit.
He gave up sooner than I expected.
I am Kaito Kameyama.
-It was...
-I'm going outside Tokyo.
It's fun here.
Since there are no laws,
you can steal or kill
without being punished.
When I'm playing a game,
it's like nothing matters at all!
It feels pretty damn good.
I fucking hate this place.
That's why I smoke weed...
and cower.
What is this world?
What are these games?
Who the heck is organizing them?
Are you alright?
Don't just film us! Give me a hand!
You must be insane!
Here, life is meaningless.
Human life has no value.
Is that what this world
is trying to teach us?
Arisu...
Do it!
You couldn't return, right?
We'll all die!
There.
Thank you.
When...
I heard Kyuma's last words,
I realized something.
They had originally been players.
But now,
they'd become citizens
and were making games here.
It means...
even if we clear all these games,
we might not be able to go back.
The world
that we came from may not exist anymore.
Did I...
kill Tatta...
just for that?
That can't be true.
I'm sure we can go back.
I'm going for it.
I'll keep playing the games.
For Tatta's sake too.
Are you really leaving?
I'm still worried about Ann and Chishiya.
I'm going to look for them.
We'll need more teammates if
we're going to defeat the King of Spades.
If we can clear even one game,
we'll be closer to our goal.
Don't you worry.
I swear, we'll meet again someday.
Usagi, you need to take a little break.
Arisu!
You take care of Usagi.
Okay, take care of yourselves.
Oh, well.
Wish I could go to some unknown place.
It would be bad if zombies
were to appear in Shibuya, huh?
If they're all bitten here,
they will all turn into zombies!
Stop it with the zombie talk,
and think about which shop to go to.
But if zombies were to appear,
I guess only Karube would survive.
You'd knock those zombies out
with one punch.
No, it wouldn't be me.
You'd be the one to survive, Arisu.
Me? Why?
I'm sure you're the one who will survive.
What's your deal?
You think your life's over now?
What?
Quit making that face
like it's the end of the world.
I wasn't sure what you wanted to tell us,
but it was pretty stupid.
Is your life so pathetic that missing
some dumb interview will end it?
Who cares about that stupid shit?
Your dad pulled some strings?
Just blow it off
and figure out what to do later.
Arisu.
In life, even when it seems like
you've hit a dead end,
you turn a corner, and there'll be
a narrow road leading you further.
That's not very convincing
coming from a part-time bartender.
Then you say something cool.
You have any good ideas?
Well, let me see...
What? You don't?
-But what you said was cool.
-Oh, fuck off.
My mind went totally blank.
Enough of your shit, man.
It's mugwort.
Say, why don't we go hunting?
We're out of food, you know?
If we don't get anything,
it'll be weeds for dinner again.
Here!
If you want meat, then give me a hand.
Arisu!
Get to it, would you, Arisu?
There's no food for dinner.
Arisu! There! Over there!
Over there!
I see it.
You almost had it!
What's your problem?
Darn it!
Over there!
Oh! Over here!
Usagi, over there!
Oh, darn!
Arisu, over there!
Oh, I can't get it.
It's just no good.
No dinner tonight.
But I'm starving.
Are you okay?
The film...
Film?
It's in here.
He must have been a photographer.
This is 8mm film.
Do you watch it with this?
I am Kaito Kameyama.
In this world
where electronics don't work,
I want to use this 8mm film camera
to make a record of this world
in order to discover
the truth and reality of it.
It's fun here.
Since there are no laws,
you can steal or kill
without being punished.
When I'm playing a game,
it's like nothing matters at all!
It feels pretty damn good.
I fucking hate this place.
That's why I smoke weed
and cower.
It has been 26 days
since everyone disappeared.
What are you doing?
That's Ann.
Excuse me. What's wrong?
The fish are increasing in numbers
and the vegetation is becoming denser.
The farther from the city center,
the more the city is
covered in vegetation.
Isn't it because there are no more humans?
Of course, that's part of it.
But the vegetation is growing
at an incredible pace.
Each person came to this world
at different times,
and food rotted quickly,
so time isn't flowing normally.
Where are you going?
I'm going outside of Tokyo.
I want to know just what this world is.
It has been 33 days
since everyone disappeared.
I learned something from a man I met.
A community has been established
on the outskirts of Setagaya.
I'm headed there now.
I came to this community
because I heard there's someone here
who remembers something strange.
Can you take me to them?
This way.
What is it they remember?
Do you remember
when you came to this world?
Yeah, a little bit.
So, did you see those fireworks then?
Fireworks?
Yes, I did. I saw them. I remember.
I saw them too.
This way. Come on.
This lady's story is super realistic.
Come on.
Here. She's over here.
Tell him that story about those fireworks.
Yes.
Oh...
About the fireworks?
You want to hear about the fireworks too?
Yes.
I guess nobody remembers it.
What?
When I was a child,
I had holes drilled into my skull
when I had an operation done on my brain.
That might be why...
But I seem to be the only one
who remembers everything about that day.
When the fireworks appeared in the sky...
They looked like fireworks in the sky.
But
actually, that wasn't...
fireworks...
He's here again!
The King of Spades is here again!
This film
is the only proof that I lived.
I must leave this film for others.
Something is coming.
This way, Arisu!
Watch out!
Go!
Usagi!
Hey!
Usagi?
Who's there?
Are you a citizen?
What?
I guess you aren't.
Ow...
Then why did you attack me?
If you had kept running,
you would have died.
I told him to leave you
since you'd only be a drag,
but he carried you
all the way here anyhow.
"He"?
You'd better go thank him, Arisu.
How come you know my name?
He told me.
But be careful.
Since you interfered with our plan,
he's in a bad mood.
Aguni...
Yo, newbie.
Subtitle translation by: Brian Athey